I want people not to die and I don’t care about the rest
Я хочу чтобы люди не умирали а остальное
in general Russia will win, Ukraine
мне в целом плевать победит Россия украи
really want people not to die yes
реально хотите чтобы люди не умирали да
What needs to be done so that people don’t
Что нужно сделать чтобы люди не
die I have no idea
умирали Я понятия не
Hello, do you have any questions
имею Здравствуйте какие-нибудь вопросы
for me I’m from the city of Khmelnitsk
есть ко мне Я из города Хмельницке Вы
Where are you from?  I was born or where I am
откуда я от где я родился или где я
now and where I was born and where now
сейчас и где родились и где сейчас
I was born in Moscow I live I now in the
Родился я в Москве проживаю Я сейчас в
city of Tokyo I realized how long ago they left from
городе Токио понял как давно уехали из
Russia for the fourth month already And what did
России четвёртый месяц уже как А что
they leave under They [ __ ] me Ani This is
уехали под Заебали они меня Ани Это
who our dear
кто наше многоуважаемые
government understood And what exactly  in
правительство понял А что именно в
Tokyo very much Japan
Токио очень Япония
likes to live comfortably here
нравится комфортно здесь жить
pleasantly you work as a
приятно работаете кем
programmer I understand
программистом понял
how you feel about the fact that Russia
а как относитесь к тому что Россия
attacked Ukraine and extremely negatively
напала на Украину а крайне отрицательно
out of great
из большой
sadness do something to
печалью что-нибудь делаете для того
reduce your sadness But I left
чтобы уменьшить свою печаль А вот уехал
about the outside and don’t look at them
об наруже на их не
I’m a little  pay I’m talking a little about
смотреть Я немножко плать Я немножко про
something else, you don’t have to say what
другое можете не озвучивать что
exactly is simple or Do something that will
конкретно просто или Делайте что-то что
reduce your print I
уменьшить вашу печать
play sports with my wife I spend a lot of time in
занимаюсь с женой много времени провожу
Ukraine you help with a
Украине помогаете
dog I don’t help Ukraine
собакой Украине не помогаю А
Why Good question,
почему Хороший вопрос
but for some reason I have the feeling that any
а у меня почему-то ощущение что любые
money I pay  they will go to the extent of
деньги которые я заплачу пойдут на то
fighting further. But I don’t want this,
чтобы воевать дальше А мне этого не
but perhaps there are some organizations
но возможно есть какие-то организации
that purely humanitarian help, you could
которые чисто гуманитарка помогают можно
donate to them like this, if people Yes from the
задонатить так ели если люди Да из
Russian Federation who left will
Российской Федерации которые выехали
donate to the ZSU Yes, to continue to fight Yes,
донатят на зсу Да воевать дальше Да это
how long until the Victory of Ukraine  before the Victory of
до какого до Победы Украины до Победы
Russia You want Russia to defeat
России Вы хотите чтобы Россия победила
Ukraine, the armed forces
Украину мне ВС
died for me anyway, and I don’t care about the rest,
равно умирали а остальное мне в целом
Russia will win, you really want
плевать победит Россия у реально хотите
people not to die, yes What needs to be
чтобы люди не умирали да Что нужно
done so that people do
сделать чтобы люди не
n’t die I have no idea,
умирали Я понятия не имею хорошо
look well, but you can, for example, at the
смотрите А вы можете например на
turnstiles Yes,
турникеты Да вот
there is, for example, they collect for tourniquets for
есть собирают например на турникеты на
medicine for the military Yes, so that they don’t
медицину для военных Да чтобы они не
die so that there is no
умирали чтобы нет
loss, this is normal, this is something I could
потери это нормально это это я мог бы
donate to, I just really didn’t
задонатить я просто об этом правда не
think about it, it’s good, just look, here I am, this is
думал хороша просто смотри я вот я вот
how I address all Russians Yes, I’m appealing, I
как ко всем россиянам Да обращаюсь вот
just left there and  I’m sitting here, it won’t
просто уехал там и сижу это ничего не
change anything Yes, we need to help stop this
изменит Да надо помогать это остановить
Yes, someone can donate to the ZSU Maybe they’re afraid
Да донать на зсу кто-то Может там боится
to donate to the ZSU or don’t want to go there,
донатить на зсу или не хочет там
for example, here’s the moral suffering that he
например вот моральное страждань что он
kind of supports Won, he’ll
как бы поддерживает вону какую-то херню
come up with some kind of crap there Yes But it’s possible for medicine,
там придумает Да Во но можно на медицину
yes  tactical type donate there is
да тактическую типа донатить есть
collected Yes there is for the victims they are collected Yes there
собирают Да есть пострадавшим собирают
is such Yes because if for
Да есть такое Да потому что если
example
например
uh we Donate to the victims Yes to
ээ мы Скидываемся пострадавшим Да на
help So that means we won’t chip in for
помощь Так значит мы не скинемся на
something else if people from abroad
что-то другое если люди изза границы так
just donate to the victims to help
само скидываются пострадавшим на помощь
yes So that means we no longer need  will
да Значит нам уже не нужно будет
close this moment, we will
закрывать этот момент мы будем
do something else, you can always
заниматься чем-то другим всегда можно
find how to realize yourself, especially as a
найти как ээ себя вот реализовать тем
programmer I am also a programmer I
более программистом Я тоже программист Я
understand that you If you are a programmer If
понимаю что вы Если вы программист Если
you are a good programmer then you will find some kind of
вы хороший программист так то вы найдёте
conditionally a couple of euros or
каких-то там условно пару евро да или
something  Yen Japanese Yes, what do you have here
там ен японский Да что там у вас вот
to donate to some good cause
чтобы перекинуть на какое-то благое дело
? Yes, I’m sure that there are simply yes, there are a lot of
Да я уверен что просто есть да куча есть
children. Yes, there are funds that take care of
детей Да есть фонды которые занимаются
children. Yes, who were left there without
детьми Да которые остались там без
parents, for example, or else, that is, you
родителей например или ещё то есть
can always find something to
всегда можно найти чем
help, this is an idea
помочь это мысль
good, the only thing is that it’s
хорошая вот Единственное что из Японии
quite difficult to transfer money from Japan
довольно тяжело деньги переводить за
abroad. But this is a solvable issue, and in the World Cup.
границу Но это вопрос решаемый а в ЧМ В
What is the difficulty of transferring money from Japan
чём тяжесть перевода из Японии за
abroad? Local banks are quite
границу тут банки местные довольно
stubborn and
твердолобый
conservative; they require a million of all kinds of
консервативные требуют Миллион всяких
confirmations and statements in order for it to be
подтверждений и заявлений для того чтобы
difficult for a neighbor to transfer money from an
тут деньги соседу тяжело перевести со
account to  the bill is here And for abroad there are
счёта на счёт вот А уж за границу Там
a million questions plus I am gaijin plus I am
миллион вопросов плюс Я гайдзин плюс Я
from an unfriendly country gaijin there
из недружественный страны гайдзин там ко
will be a billion questions for me where and why am
мне миллиард вопросов будет куда и зачем
I going abroad
я за границу
only Japanese yes yes yes yes Japanese
деч только японские да да да да японских
banks Yes
банков Да
screw it Well this issue can still be solved But for
капец Ну это вопрос всё равно решае А
example it’s good  but look, here you are as a
например хорошо а вот смотри вот вы как
programmer. Maybe you’ve heard about such
программист Может вы слышали про такие
systems. Like PayPal there, Pioner
там системы Как там PayPal там Pioner
there, and others in PayPal, you register using
там и другие в пейпа ты регистрируешься
your national document, and
по твоему национальному документу вот а
this is my national document: I have a passport of the
так национальный документ у меня паспорт
Russian Federation, they tell me that
Российской Федерации они мне говорят что
they’re sorry for all the service for you Now
извините для вас всё обслуживание Сейчас
closed and denied Uh-huh For me, the most
закрыто и отказано Угу Для меня самый
realistic option is just
реальный вариант - это крипта только
some kind of crypt, but that’s also Also an option, damn, in
какая-то но это тоже Тоже вариант блин
short, I never thought that for a
короче я никогда не думал что для
person who left the Russian
человека который выехал из Российской
Federation for Japan it would be so difficult to
Федерации в Японию настолько сложно
find a way to somehow harass Well, the
найти способ как-то задонать Ну
Russian Federation is smaller here  the role
Российская Федерация тут меньшую роль
influences the big role of Japan, it influences
влияет большую роль Японии именно влияет
local banks very, very much, they took
местные банки очень-очень такие забори
us away, for example, I got donations from people
нас вот например мне было донатили люди
from South Korea from the USA from Britain from
из Южной Кореи из США из Британии из
Spain damn it from the Czech Republic from wherever you want and
Испании блин из Чехии откуда не хочешь
no one from Japan yet. Now I
да из Японии пока никто не Вот теперь я
understand why I got from Japan  they won’t
понял че мне из Японии не
donate there is a problem with the bank. I understand that
донатят там проблема с банкой Я понял
we will need to contact our
надо будет чтобы мы обратились к нашему
Ministry of Foreign Affairs so that they
министерству иностранных дел чтобы они
somehow work out this issue in Poland,
как-то проработали этот вопрос польским
not with the Polish but with the Japanese embassy.
не с польским а с японским посольством
Yes, so that they somehow talk to their
Да чтобы они как-то поговорили со своими
banks, so that it would be easier for money to go to Ukraine
банками Чтобы проще было на Украину
translate Well, damn, it’s a shame that
деньги переводить Ну блин а то обидно
the Japanese are missing so much, by the way, they recently
столько пропадает японцы кстати недавно
conveyed this to you, it seems like there’s a lot of things, not exactly a lot, it doesn’t happen a lot does
передали кажется много много всего не не
n’t happen with
именно много не бывает много не бывает с
the volume of war that is going on,
тем объёмом войны который идёт да то
yes, that is, I just imagine that there are a
есть просто я просто представляю что
huge number of people in Japan now
сейчас в Японии огромное количество
like this  There are people from Russia who
людей вот так из России есть которые
want to donate, yes, but damn it’s just that
хотят вот задонатить да но блин просто
Japanese banks don’t spend money, we need to
японские банки не проводят на надо
somehow come up with some kind of scheme for how people
как-то придумать какую-то схему как люди
from Japan can transfer money,
из Японии могут перевести деньги это
damn it, I didn’t even think that there is such a
блин я даже не задумался что есть такая
serious problem, think think yes yes
проблема серьёзная думаете думайте да да
[music]
[музыка]
I wonder what else there might be, I don’t know the real
Интересно а какие ещё могут быть не знаю
way out of this situation. Well,
пути выхода из этой ситуации реально Ну
somehow it can’t be that it would
это же как-то не может быть что бе
be impossible for Japan to transfer
Японии вообще невозможно было перевести
money at all. No, well, the
деньги нет
most
ну самый кажется именно массовый
realistic option seems to be a massive one - it’s to
реальный вариант - это именно в Японии
organize some kind of money collection in Japan  a
организовать сбор денег какую-то
Japanese organization so that it is already As a
японскую организацию чтобы она уже Как
legal entity somewhere Transfer it to
юридическое лицо куда-нибудь Переводи бы
Vitya This is the most realistic option from the point of
Вите Это самый реальный вариант с точки
view of the Japanese government, they will
зрения японского правительства им этот
like this option the most, I’m sure And look, it turns out
вариант больше всего понравится я уверен
that in Japan
А так смотрите а получается что в Японии
you cannot transfer from your account
вы не можете со своего счёта перевести
to there using Swift  like on the
на там по свифту типа на
account, well, it’s possible, but it’s very
счёт ну это это можно но это очень типа
bureaucratic because you’re Swift there
бюрократических потому что ты Swift там
Swift or visa Yes, it’s a payment system,
Swift или виза Да это платёжная система
everything is clear, but it’s
всё понятно но взаимодей
not me personally as a user who interacts with the suite and the visa, but
со свитом и с визой не я лично как
my bank interacts
пользователь а банк мой взаимодействует
and when you want something from the account
и когда хочешь что-нибудь со счёта на
you ask your bank to transfer to an account,
счёт перевести ты банк свой просишь
transfer to such and such an account and he already
переведи мне на такой-то счёт а он уже
uses the visa system or he already
использует систему виза или он уже
uses Swift or whatever, so
использует Swift или всё что угодно вот
to the local bank. You can’t just come and Well,
и в местный банк Нельзя просто прийти и
that is, I’m used to what’s in the
Ну то есть я-то привык к тому что в
application  in general, everything can be done
приложении вообще всё можно сделать
here in the application, you can just
здесь в приложении можно разве что
look at the balance on your account and
остаток на счету у себя посмотреть а
transfer something somewhere. So
куда-нибудь что-нибудь перевез Это вот
you go to the bank, write an application,
идёшь в банк заявление пишешь
pay a commission. I just thought.
платишь комиссию Я так просто подумал
If such a problem is from Japan, there must be a
Если такая проблема из Японии это навер
lot of people who wrote about it in  on the Internet
куча людей об этом писали в интернете
So I entered the Swift translation from Japan,
Вот я ввёл типа Swift перевод из Японии
like there are no problems at all, no one
типа вообще нет никаких проблем никто не
writes about the
пишет про
problems, these are financial problems in telegram, the
проблемы это финансовые в телеграме
Japanese finance chat, you can type and
чатик финансов Японии можешь набрать
read Wiki there, all sorts of things about how to
почитать там Вики всякие про то как это
do it, there are quite extensive
делать там вот довольно развесистые
instructions about how to do it,
инструкции про то как как это совершить
that is  I’m saying it’s not impossible It’s
то есть говорю это не невозможно Это
just inconveniently understood What do you think,
просто неудобно понял А как вы считаете
in general, Crimea,
вообще вот Крым
whose Crimea is Ukrainian, understood here at least
чей Крым украинский понял тут хоть
unequivocally Okay, do you have
однозначно Окей у вас ко мня есть
any questions for me, no, I
какие-то вопросы нет у меня вопросы
don’t have any questions, I’m just answering the question
отсутствуют Я только отвечаю на вопрос
Okay, why are you asking this question Like you
Окей А зачем вы вот вопрос Типа вы
you choose Ukraine
выбираете Украину
on purpose Yes, I have Ukraine today
специально Да у меня Украина сегодня
Why it depends from day to day I just
Зачем от дня к Дню зависит Я просто
turn it on and see how many
включаю и смотрю насколько сегодня вот
people with good sound with a
попадаются люди с хорошим звуком с
good camera come across today. Sometimes you put on
хорошей камерой Вот иногда ставишь
Ukraine and you can talk, there is no noise
Украину и можешь поговорить нету шумов
and nothing, sometimes you put on Russia,
никаких и ничего иногда ставишь Росси
why are you  choose Ukraine What do
для для чего вы выбираете Украину О чём
you want to talk about with
вы хотите поговорить с
the Ukrainians What will they ask me about? I
украинцами О чём они меня спросят Я же
answer the
отвечаю на
questions: why do
вопросы а
you have some kind of secret
зачем чем вы обладаете какими-то тайными
knowledge?
знаниями нут нет Надо же разговор как-то
I choose
какая Вот например я выхожу э выбираю
Russia in order to somehow convince
Россию для того чтобы как-то переубедить
some Russian, at least out of a hundred Yes, to
какого-то россиянина хотя бы но из ста
sow the seed of truth somewhere. And you
Да где-то посеять зену истину А вы
choose the Ukrainians. Why am I
выбираете украинцев Для
saying that I put on the day the country
чего говорю я ставлю в день ту страну
where it’s better, I just come across people
где получше мне просто попадается люди
with connections, that’s all  there is sometimes in
со связью вот и всё то есть иногда в
Ukraine Sometimes I put Ukraine and here it
Украине Иногда я ставлю Украину и вот
goes Yes, in general, what’s the point?
идёт Да вообще для чего какой смысл
Give me a question. What is the point of your
давай вопрос Какой смысл ваших
conversations with people from
разговоров с людьми из
Ukraine? It’s the same as the point of
Украины э такой же как и смысл
conversations with people from Russia, just
разговоров с людьми из России просто
talk to someone in Russian
поговорить с кем-нибудь по-русски потому
because I  I haven’t spoken to anyone in Russian for a long time,
что я Давненько ни с кем по-русски не
otherwise you just want to
разговаривал а то вы просто свои хотите
fly away, some kind of selfish
улететь своё какой-то эгоистические
interest, uh, to communicate. Absolutely right, yes,
интерес ээ пообщаться Совершенно верно
absolutely
понял да совершенно
right,
верно
and Yes, it has now dawned on me And I
а и Да До меня теперь дошло А я так
understand that the questions are over, then all the
понял вопросы кончились тогда всего
best,
хорошего
dodik, write what you  you think about this
[__] напишите что вы думаете про этого
character
персонажа
just to talk Why the hell should you
просто поговорить Нахрена тебе
talk Choose If you want to
разговаривать Выбирай Если хочешь
talk Choose Russia and I’ll
поговорить Выбирай Россию да и что-то
get through to them Tell me that in Japan it’s
достучусь к ним Рассказывай что в Японии
really better to live, like, than there in
реально жить лучше да типа чем там в
your jam-packed Rashkin, and
твоём забитом короче блин рашкине да
comparing some economic
сравнивая какие-то там экономические
political models and  so on Otherwise,
политические модели и так дальше А то
damn it, I can’t, I can’t, I
блин то не могу то не могу не на войну
wouldn’t do it for the war because it would make it
бы не делал потому что она из этого
longer. This is when they say that I
дольше будет Вот это когда говорят что я
wouldn’t donate to
бы не донатил на
uh ZSU Because this is how I make the
ээ зсу Потому что таким образом я делаю
war last
чтобы война была
longer this this this  Russian
дольше это вот это это Российская
agenda Yes, which also says that there is no
повестка Да которая также говорят что не
need to give Ukraine weapons because
надо давать Украине оружие потому что
then the war will only last longer. Yes, it
тогда война только дольше будет Да так
turns out the other way around. If you don’t give Ukraine
наоборот получается Если не дать Украине
weapons, then Russia will take over Ukraine and
оружие да то росия захватит Украину и
evil will win.
зло победит пись на й teleg прям зараз